<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Muscat</string>
    <string name="content_description">Tour Picture</string>
    <string name="category_attraction">Attraction</string>
    <string name="category_museum">Museum</string>
    <string name="category_bpark">Beaches And Parks</string>
    <string name="category_restaurant">Restaurant</string>
    <!--Details of Attraction.-->
    <string name="attraction1">Al Alam Palace</string>
    <string name="attraction2">Bhimma Sinkhole</string>
    <string name="attraction3">Mutrah Corniche</string>
    <string name="attraction4">Mutrah Souq</string>
    <string name="attraction5">Sultan Qaboos Grand Mosque</string>
    <string name="attraction6">Wahiba Sand</string>
    <string name="alalam_Info">
        With its funnel-like gold and blue pillars and lone flagpole extending like an antenna from its flat roof, Al Alam Palace (Sultan\'s Palace)
        is one of Oman’s most striking examples of contemporary Islamic architecture. The palace, built in 1972, is set between the Mirani and
        Jalali forts along the coast of Muscat’s Old Town and is one of six royal residences belonging to His Majesty Sultan Qaboos.\n
        Over the years, the ceremonial palace has received a number of important visitors, including Queen Elizabeth of England and
        Queen Beatrix of the Netherlands, as well as hosting a number of official functions and ceremonies. Although the palatial buildings
        are closed to the public, visitors can still enjoy views of Imam Sultan bin Ahmed’s masterpiece from the surrounding palace gardens or
        the waterfront of the nearby Muscat Port.
    </string>
    <string name="mosque_Info">
        Muscat\’s most magnificent religious building and the only mosque in Oman to open its doors to tourists, the Sultan Qaboos Grand Mosque is one
        of the city\’s most popular attractions. Built in the Ghubrah suburb back in 2001, the landmark building is an impressive feat of contemporary
        Islamic architecture and one of the largest mosques in the Gulf, with the 40,000-square-meter grounds able to accommodate an incredible 20,000
        worshippers at one time.
        \n
        Set within a vast walled compound, overlooked by 5 towering minarets, the Grand Mosque encompasses two prayer halls encircled by a courtyard,
        gardens and a series of water features. Incorporating elements of Omani, Persian and Egyptian design, the complex is sculpted entirely from
        pristine white Indian sandstone and includes a Ladies’ Prayer Hall, library and meeting rooms. The crowning glory of the mosque is the lavish
        central prayer hall, a gleaming mass of white and grey marble adorned with elaborate tile work and featuring a 14-meter tall Swarovski crystal
        chandelier and the second largest carpet in the world – a 70-meter-long, hand-woven Iranian rug. Beneath the dramatic 50-meter high gold,
        latticed dome, there is space for up to 6,600 prayer mats.
        \n
        While the mosque welcomes visitors, non-Muslims may only enter the main prayer hall during designated times and both men and women entering the
        mosque are required to follow the dress code – arms, legs and hair (women only) must be covered.
    </string>
    <string name="souq_Info">
        One of the oldest traditional souks (marketplaces) in the Arab world, the Muttrah souk has a history stretching back over 200 years and has earned
        acclaim throughout Oman for its varied array of both local and imported goods – thanks in large part to its strategic position at the mouth of Muscat
        Harbor. Known locally as the Al Dhalam souk, which translates as \‘Darkness\’ in Arabic, the souk takes its name from the network of narrow streets
        that run between Khour Bimba and the Al Lawatiya Mosque, where the stalls are so cramped together the sunlight can\’t make it through the cracks.
        \n
        Navigating the dimly lit stalls and maze-like alleyways is all part of the experience and shopping in the souks is one of the top pastimes
        for visitors to Oman.  Exploring the myriad of stalls reveals a host of local goods like Frankincense, perfumes and fresh spices, alongside
        traditional handicrafts like Khanjers (Omani knives), Bedu jewelry and colorful hookah pipes. Pay a visit to the Gold Souk, where the honeycomb
        of stalls are laden with gold and silver jewelry, tuck into some local street food, then put your haggling skills to the test as you scour the
        markets for unique Omani souvenirs.
    </string>
    <string name="sand_Info">
        Stretching over 125 miles (200 kilometers) from the Eastern Hajar Mountains to the Arabian Sea, the Wahiba Sands desert (Sharqiya Sands) is Oman\’s
        adventure playground. Named after the nomadic Wahiba Bedouin tribes, the region is known for its amber-colored sands and towering sand dunes,
        some standing up to 330 feet (100 meters) high.
        \n\n<b>The Basics</b>\n\n
        A desert safari is a must to experience Oman\’s natural wonders, whether its dune bashing in a 4x4, taking a sunset camel ride, or zipping
        through the dunes on a sandboard or quad bike. Small-group or private tours leave from Muscat or Bidiyah, and typically include a picnic lunch
        at a traditional desert camp, swimming at Wadi Bani Khalid, and a variety of optional activities.
        \n\n<b>Things to Know Before You Go</b>\n\n
        Heading off-road in the desert is only recommended as part of a guided tour with an experienced local guide.\n
        It can get hot in the desert and there\’s little shade, so bring a hat, sunscreen, and plenty of water. A scarf to protect your face from the
        sand is also recommended.
        \nThere is no cellphone coverage or Wi-Fi in the area.
        \n\n<b>How to Get There</b>\n\n
        The Wahiba Sands desert is about a 3-hour drive from Muscat, off the Muscat-Sur Highway at Al-Mintirib. The most popular way to visit is as part
        of a guided tour.
        \n\n<b>When to Get There</b>\n\n
        The best time to visit Wahiba Sands is during the winter months from October to April. During the summer (May to September), temperatures can
        reach 104°F (40°C) or more.
        \n\n<b>Wildlife of the Wahiba Sands</b>\n\n
        Wahiba Sands is renowned for its unique desert ecosystem and surprisingly rich biodiversity. Some 180 native species of plants, as well as more
        than 200 species of animals, can be found in the desert, including vipers, desert hares, sand foxes, and birds. The best times for wildlife
        watching are at sunrise or sunset, but guides will often point out animal tracks as you trek through the desert.
    </string>
    <string name="sink_Info">
         The Bimmah Sinkhole, located in Hawiyat Najm Park (مـتـنزه هـويـة نـجـم), literally meaning Meteor Fall Park in Arabic, is a sinkhole in the
        Muscat governorate of Oman. You can get to the sinkhole in about 1.5 hours from Muscat, and despite being technically in Muscat governorate,
        the sinkhole is actually very close to Al Sharqiyah region just off the high way to Sur, few kilometers before Tiwi. You can spend a couple of
        minutes just taking pictures of this amazing sinkhole, or more than an hour swimming in the clear turquoise water, but either way you should
        definitely stop here if you are heading to Al Sharqiyah governorate. We usually visit Bimmah Sinkhole on our way back from a trip to Wadi Shab
        or Wadi Al Arbaeen.
    </string>
    <string name="corniche_Info">
        Mutrah stretches along an attractive corniche of latticed buildings and mosques; it looks spectacular at sunset when the light casts shadows
        across the serrated crescent of mountains, while pavements, lights and fountains invite an evening stroll or a bike ride.
        \n
        The initiative to relocate the industrial elements of the port and redevelop the dockside for tourism is well underway with the refurbishment
        of the fish market complete. The port will provide a permanent home for Shabab Oman, the country\'s magnificent fully rigged training ship,
        which is soon to be retired now that its replacement has been commissioned. In the meantime, the harbour is home to His Majesty\'s dhow,
        visiting cruise ships and assorted naval vessels.
    </string>
    <!--Details of Museum.-->
    <string name="museum1">Bait Al Zubair Museum</string>
    <string name="museum2">Children Museum</string>
    <string name="museum3">Museum of Illusions</string>
    <string name="museum4">National Museum</string>
    <string name="museum5">Oman Natural History Museum</string>
    <string name="museum6">Sultans Armed Forces Museum</string>
    <string name="zubair_Info">CDATA
        Bait Al Zubair is a museum, located on Al Saidiya Street, Old Muscat, Oman.\n
        The museum has an extensive collection of ancient weapons, including khanjar, household equipments,and costumes
        (most of which derive from the owner\'s private collection). Outside the museum is a full-scale Omani village and souk.
        \n\n<b>Visiting Hours</b>\n\n
            Sat To Thu - 9:30 AM - 6:00 PM
    </string>
    <string name="national_Info">
        The National Museum - Sultanate of Oman, established in 2013, is the Sultanate\'s flagship cultural institution,
        showcasing the nation\'s heritage from the earliest human settlement in the Oman Peninsula some two million years ago through to the present day.
        As a national institution with global outreach, the museum is dedicated to ensuring Oman\'s cultural heritage is understood and appreciated not only
        within the Sultanate, but also internationally. Further, it aims to provide opportunities for cultural expression,
        innovation and the transfer of traditional skills and knowledge from one generation to the next.
        The museum is located in the heart of Muscat in a magnificent purpose-designed building. The total area of the building is 13,700 square metres
        (147,000 sq ft), including 4,000 square metres (43,000 sq ft) allocated for 14 permanent galleries - The Land and the People Gallery,
        Maritime History Gallery, Arms and Armour Gallery, Aflaj Gallery, Currency Gallery, Prehistory and Ancient History Galleries,
        Splendours of Islam Gallery, Oman and the World Gallery, Intangible Heritage Gallery and Renaissance Gallery, among others.
        A further 400 square metres (4,300 sq ft) are allocated for temporary exhibitions. The National Museum houses 5466 objects and
        offers 43 digital immersive experiences, a fully equipped Learning Centre, state-of-the-art conservation facilities, a UHD cinema and
        discovery areas for children. It features an integrated infrastructure for special needs and is the first museum in the Middle East to adopt
        Arabic Braille script for the visually impaired. It also houses the region\'s first open-plan museum storage concept, where visitors can learn
        about the various processes that artefacts go through before they are put on display.
        \n\n<b>Visiting Hours</b>\n\n
            Fri - 2:00 PM - 6:00 PM\n
            Sat to Thu - 10:00 AM - 5:00 PM

    </string>
    <string name="armed_Info">
        The Sultan\'s Armed Forces Museum is a military history museum, located in the 150-year-old Bait Al Falaj Fort, once the headquarters for
        Sultan Said bin Sultan\'s Armed Forces, located on Al Mujamma Street, in the Ruwi area near Muscat, Oman. It was graciously inaugurated in 1988
        by His Majesty Sultan Qaboos, the supreme commander of the Armed Forces.\n
        The museum has an extensive collection related to Oman\'s military history, national conflicts; with displays of weapons (such as guns and cannons),
        service uniforms, an external display of military vehicles, military music instruments, medals and even an jet aircraft ejector seat and a parachute
        on display.
        \n\n<b>Visiting Hours</b>\n\n
            Sun To Thu - 7:30 AM - 1:30 PM\n
            Sat - 9:00 AM - 11:45 AM
    </string>
    <string name="illusion_Info">
    The Museum of Illusion in Oman brings you a space suitable both for social and entertaining tours into the world of illusions which has delighted
    all generations. It’s a perfect place for new experiences and fun with friends and family and it’s unique in this part of the Arab World.
    Enter the fascinating world of illusion which will trick your confidence in senses, but amaze you by doing it.
    \n\n<b>Visiting Hours</b>\n\n
           Thu To Fri - 10:00 AM - 11:00 PM\n
           Sat To Wed - 10:00 AM - 10:00 PM
</string>
    <string name="natural_Info">
        The Natural History Museum of Oman is a natural history museum, located at the Ministry of Heritage and Culture complex, Al Khuwair,
        opposite the Zawawi Mosque in Muscat, Oman.\n
        The museum opened on 20 December 1985, and has detailed coverage of Oman\'s flora and fauna, with displays on indigenous mammals, insects,
        and birds and botanical gardens. One of the highlights of the museum is the whale hall: it houses the huge skeleton of a sperm whale,
        which was washed up on the Omani coastline in the 1986.The museum contains marine and animal fossils and ancient mammals such as monkeys and
        elephants primitive, teeth Deinotherium and Gomphotherium, and stuffed animals: Arabian leopard. Caracal. Arabian Oryx. Arabian wolf. Arab Red fox.
        Ghazal skeleton Arabic. Ibex Arabic. Flamengo. Birds. Crow. Owl. Reptiles. Snakes\' lizards. Snails and shells.
        \n\n<b>Visiting Hours</b>\n\n
           Sun To Thu - 9:30 AM - 1:30 PM\n
           Sat - 9:00 AM - 1:00 PM
    </string>
    <string name="children_Info">
        The Oman Children\'s Museum is a children\'s science museum, located near Qurum Nature Park off Sultan Qaboos Street in a white-domed building
        in Muscat, Oman.\n
        The museum was established by the Ministry of National Heritage and Culture and opened on November 17, 1990 by Sultan Qaboos bin Said al Said
        on the 20th National Day celebration in Oman. The museum has 45 exhibits and two demonstrations and comprises 10,000 square feet (930 m2).
        It was the first science museum in Oman and is visited by around 50,000 visitors annually. The museum is currently run by a former school teacher,
        Samirah Ahmed al Raisi, who has run the museum for over six years.\n
        The museum addresses the scientific ways of human life and the exhibition section is divided into three parts;
        The Human life, Physics and observation which investigates the progression of science through the ages.\n
        The museum has many hands-on displays. These include experiences of a fake electric shock, trigger a lightning bolt, launching a hot air balloon,
        photographing your own shadow, and sending message through a whisper dish. There is also a display named "Eye Spy", which is series of perception panels
        with illusions designed to offer some insight into how your eyes and brain see things differently.
       \n\n<b>Visiting Hours</b>\n\n
           Mon To Wed - 8:00 AM - 5:00 PM\n
           Thu To Sun - 8:00 AM - 1:30 PM
    </string>
    <!--Details of Beaches and Parks.-->
    <string name="beach1">Al Sifa Beach</string>
    <string name="beach2">Pebble Beach</string>
    <string name="beach3">Qantab Beach</string>
    <string name="park1">Kalbouh Park</string>
    <string name="park2">Qurum Park</string>
    <string name="park3">Riyam Park</string>

    <string name="sifa_Info">
        Life is all about balance at Jebel Sifah. Yacht owners are assured a safe haven for
        their boats at the sophisticated marina, which also acts as a chic hub for the wider
        community, and golfers will be rewarded with breathtaking views when they tee off at
        the nine-hole Harradine golf course. Some of Oman\’s most exclusive hotels and resorts
        can be found here, welcoming guests from around the world, while those looking for a home,
        weekend getaway or solid investment will find attractive freehold residential opportunities
        in the community\’s villas and apartment offerings. The surrounding landscape is a dream for
        the active and adventurous, as well as those in search of tranquillity.
        \nThe beach at As Sifah is ideal for desert-lovers who don\'t want to forgo the sea.
        Its fine, deep golden sand makes it difficult to stroll along the beach.
        Since the beach at the village of As Sifah is not developed for tourists and there are
        few opportunities to buy food and drinks, you need to bring your own. Its open aspect
        without windbreaks makes it good for various types of water sports, including surfing,
        kite-surfing, sailing or windsurfing, provided you bring your own equipment.\n\n
        How to get the camping spots : \n\n
        Camping spots on Sifah beach are easy to find. Head towards Yiti and follow the signs for
        Jebel Sifah. Enter the complex and go right at the third roundabout. Drive past the
        apartment buildings and the beach will be on your left. Choose the most suitable looking site.
        \n\nGPS of camping spot:   N23° 23’ 47.87” E58° 48’ 12.737”
    </string>
    <string name="pebble_Info">
        Oman Pebble beach is on Muscat - Sur Coastal road and very close to Wadi Shab another
        beautiful tourist location. This beach is full of different shapes and colors of pebbles.
        The sea looks fantastic with two to three colors. The crystal clear waters would be ideal
        for swimming and snorkeling.\n\n
        How to get there :\n\n
        From Muscat, follow Route 17 all the way to Sur, about 150 KM as if you were visiting
        Wadi Shab. Exit soon after the Wadi Shab Resort and take a u turn .
        Right goes to Wadi Shab and left ( You will be back to Coastal road ) goes to pebbles beach
        The beach is almost behind the Wadi Shab resort.\n\n
        GPS : N22° 50’ 40” E59°  14’ 32”
    </string>
    <string name="qantab_Info">
        At only 15km from the centre of Muscat, the quaint village of Qantab can be reached in
        about 25 minutes on a good day with little traffic. Directions are well signposted and as
        you approach, the road climbs a hill. When u reached the crest you will get a fantastic
        view of the village.\n
        Set amid brown, craggy hills that taper down into the sea, the village itself is quite
        small, dotted with quaint houses that face out to the sea and give their occupants
        uninterrupted views of the water.\n
        As the sun sets Qantab Beach pulses with life. This is when lots of children come
        running down to play and the locals meet up to chat by the water. The numerous fishermen
        with their fishing boats are a particular highlight. Watching them go about their handiwork
        adds an extra something to the atmosphere.\n\n
        How to get there :\n\n
        Take An Nuzhah Street through Al Wadi Al Kabir in the direction of the Al Bustan Palace.
        Take the exit to Qantab road before you reach the hotel. Stay on this road for 4km and then
        take a left towards the village. The route to Qantab is well signposted.\n\n
        GPS : N23° 33’ 43” E58° 37’ 45
    </string>
    <string name="kalbou_Info">
        Kalbuh Bay Park juts into a sea that\'s boiling with sardines.
        Located at the end of the Corniche, it makes a good pausing place on a hike between
        Mutrah and Old Muscat. Swimming on the public beach is possible for those not afraid of
        attracting an audience.\n
        Kalbuh beach is located near the Kalbuh Park in Muttrah. It is one of the best places to go
        swimming in Muscat. They even offer free swimming classes. With a great view of the park,
        the surrounding mountain and the turquoise waters, Kalbuh Beach is one of the must-visit
        beaches in Muscat.        \n\n
        Opening Hours : \n
        Sun To Sat : 9:00 AM - 10:00 PM
    </string>
    <string name="qurum_Info">
        You just cannot have enough of Qurum Natural Park, the largest park in Oman covering an
        area of over 17,00,000 sq metres, in one visit. Located in the heart of Muscat,
        this park has a huge artificial lake, numerous old trees, manicured shrubs and green lawns,
        all of which provide the much need solace away from the hustle and bustle of the city.
        The Marah Land amusement park is located adjacent to this park.       \n\n
        Opening Hours : \n
        Sun To Thu : 8:00 AM - 8:00 PM
        Fri, Sat : 9:00 AM - 12:00 PM
    </string>
    <string name="riyam_Info">
        A visit to Riyam Park, located in Mutrah, is part of the fun when you visit the Mutrah
        corniche or Old Mutrah Souq, both of which are a big draw for tourists. This is also the
        most attractive park for children because of the rides, games, and playgrounds. Spread over
        100,000 sq. metres, it also houses the iconic, giant ornamental incense burner installed atop
        a hill which offers a splendid view of the nearby harbour. \n\n
         Opening Hours : \n
        Sun To Thu : 4:00 PM - 11:00 PM
        Fri, Sat : 9:00 AM - 12:00 PM
    </string>
    <!--Details of Restaurants.-->
    <string name="restaurant1">Ananthapuri Restaurant</string>
    <string name="restaurant2">Golden Oryx Restaurant</string>
    <string name="restaurant3">Kargeen Restaurant</string>
    <string name="restaurant4">Oman Express Restaurant</string>
    <string name="restaurant5">The Cave</string>
    <string name="restaurant6">The Jungle Restaurant</string>

    <string name="res1_Info">
        Ananthapuri restaurant, located near Darsait signal,Opposite muscat muncipality,part of
        Al Shorouq group of companies commenced its exciting journey on 07th december 2008.\n
        Ananthapuri restaurant has earned a unique position in Muscat – a place that is synonymous
        to Taste, Tradition, Ambience and Agility in Service. It is a theme restaurant who serves
        authentic South Indian dishes along with variety of options in North Indian and Chinese
        cuisine.\n\n
        Opening Hours :\n\n
        Sun To Thu, Sat : 12:00 – 3:00 PM, 7:00 – 11:00 PM \n
        Fri : 1:00 - 3:00 PM, 7:00 - 11:30 PM \n\n
        Contact :\n\n
        Ananthapuri Restaurant, Opposite Muscat Muncipality\n
        Al Shorouq Hotel Apartment Building\n
        Post box: 321 | Postal code: 111\n
        Darsait | Sultanate of Oman\n
        Phone: 24706226 | Mobile: +968 97081177
    </string>
    <string name="res2_Info">
        The Golden Oryx, Muscat\’s finest chinese restaurant, offers a rich blend of szechuan,
        cantonese, thai, mongolian delicacies, in the most elegant surroundings.\n
        In more than twenty-nine years of its existence, the Golden Oryx has endeared itself
        to a cross- section of affluent Omanis, Asian and European expatriates.
        Its prime location in Ruwi with its rich, but subdued ethnic oriental décor,
        and the quaint woodwork which characterises the interior of this Restaurant,
        captures the magic of the far east. The tables, some of them large enough to seat
        a group of 12, are placed far apart, affording diners a fair degree of privacy.
        Private banquet rooms are available on the mezzanine floor for parties, from small
        groups of ten to lavish banquets for 50. Huge wall mural with pictures of the oryx link the
        restaurant inextricably with Oman. The ceiling is adorned with floral hand painted ceramic tiles.\n\n
        Opening Hours :\n\n
        Sun To Thu, Sat : 12:00 – 3:00 PM, 7:00 – 12:00 PM \n
        Fri : 1:00 - 3:30 PM, 7:00 - 12:00 PM \n\n
        Contact :\n\n
        Golden Oryx Restaurant\n
        Al Burj St, Muscat\n
        Phone : 24702266
    </string>
    <string name="res3_Info">
        Kargeen is an old Omani word for \‘little wooden cottage\’. Established in 1997 by a
        dynamic couple – Mr. Jalil Abdullah Hamza Al Asfoor and Mrs. Hana Haffadh – at Madinat Qaboos,
        Kargeen has been making quality Arabic food accessible to all. With its exquisite interiors
        and carefully planned cuisines, Kargeen takes you back into the vintage era of Omani culture and tradition.
        Kargeen is a true example of old-world charm meeting the modern-day dining experience.
        Done up in wood, wrought iron and decorated with bright rugs,
        the restaurant blends Eastern style with classical Western culture with ease.\n\n
        Opening Hours :\n\n
        Sun To Thu, Sat : 8:00 AM - 12:00 AM \n
        Fri : 12:00 PM - 12:00 AM \n\n
        Contact :\n\n
        Kargeen Restaurant\nAl Bashair St,\n Muscat\n Mobile : +968 99253351
    </string>
    <string name="res4_Info">
        One of the best restaurants in Muscat for south Indian food.It is Vegetarian restaurant.\n\n
        Opening Hours :\n\n
        Sun To Sat : 7:00 AM – 3:00 PM, 5:30 – 11:00 PM \n\n
        Contact :\n\n
        Oman Express Restaurant\n
        4359 Way, Muscat\n
        Phone : 24831329
    </string>
    <string name="res5_Info">
        This cave-like complex of seven different restaurants includes Al Manjur,
        an Omani restaurant with shuwa (slow-cooked, marinated meat dishes, OR8) on the menu.
        Smart-casual dress is expected in this Aladdin\'s cave of a restaurant.
        If the slightly austere atmosphere doesn\'t appeal, opt for Arab-style dining on the terrace
        upstairs with expansive views over the sparkling lights of Ruwi.\n\n

        Opening Hours :\n\n
        Sun To Fri : 11:00 AM - 3:30 PM, 7:00 PM - 1:00 AM \n
        Sat : 1:00 PM - 3:30 PM, 7:00 PM - 1:00 AM \n\n
        Contact :\n\n
        The Cave,\n1952 way, Darsyt Park,\n Darsyt, Muscat,\n Darsyt/Muscat 112\n Mobile : +968 99019805
    </string>
    <string name="res6_Info">
        Located in the beautiful city of Muscat, Oman, The Jungle is a novel casual restaurant
        created along the tropical rainforest theme amidst lush foliage. The location and the
        ambience of the restaurant complement the most to its unique venue. The restaurant offers
        a unique opportunity to experience the natural elements atypical of a rainforest- rain,
        thunder and lightning along with the sounds of a roaring dinosaur, chirping birds and other
        animals as you walk through it.\n\n
        Opening Hours :\n\n
        Sun To Thu : 12:00 AM - 3:00 PM, 7:00 PM - 10:30 AM \n
        Fri, Sat : 12:00 PM - 3:30 PM, 7:00 PM - 11:00 AM \n\n
        Contact :\n\n
        The Jungle Restaurant\n
        P.O.BOX 54,\n
        P.C. 100, Muscat,\n
        Sultanate Of Oman \n
        Mobile : +968 95690658
    </string>

</resources>
